Chapter 2: Dissimulation, Pt 1

Arc 1: Reconnaissance

Polyjuice potion seems to be based on two separate 'save states'. The first save state activates the moment the item(hair, skin, or similar; any DNA source seems to be a sufficient marker) is taken from the target. At this point, the target's current physical condition, including any diseases(whether symptomatic or not) and fatigue, is saved. Mental condition, including emotions and any item shown to be part of the resurrection stone's recall, does not appear to be preserved at this stage.

The second 'save state' occurs when someone takes the potion. At this moment, all aspects of their condition are saved. When the potion's duration ends, their body returns to this original condition in a process that takes approximately 2 seconds and is uninterruptable. 'Polyfluis Reverso' appears to instantly activate this process.

Further investigation of the possibility of stasis using the potion is likely necessary.

-Research log(Section IV: Bodily modifications), Tower of Hogwarts, June 1993

XxX

August 25, 1993, 9 pm: 6 days before Hogwarts opening

Colin Creevey looked to both sides nervously. Even though he had received a Hogwarts permit to work with Sapespeck over the summer in a limited capacity, he still couldn't shake the feeling that he was being watched. If any of his old muggle friends saw him, the consequences for the statute of secrecy could be horrendous. After reassuring himself that there was nobody near him, he laughed at his paranoia before readying his wand.

"Cognitio Mentis!" After the unpleasantness of last year, Flitwick had taken a month to find some charm that would allow for non-Parseltongue speakers to use the language. Eventually, he had found a substitute. The spell, originally intended for use by career duelists who wanted to refine their spells and tactics as well as avoid traps, allowed its caster to perceive all direct results of spells in their vicinity for a period of time, even those that were normally hidden. One of it's useful side effects was giving the caster the ability to understand Parseltongue coming from Sapespeck.

"Sapespeck!" A green point blinked into existence in front of him. He pulled a small pebble from his pocket and tossed it forward. The green speck flashed and emitted something that was both a sound and not at the same time, and the pebble stopped midair, dropping straight down.

Colin grinned. Harry was right, the spell definitely could produce pressure waves. Now, for the next step. He dropped to his knees and picked up the pebble before standing and readying his wand again.

"Sapespeck Maxima!" 16 specks flashed into existence in front of him, grouped into 3 pairs and one clump of ten. He lifted the pebble again, bringing it into line with the first pair. He wasn't quite sure about this part, but Harry had gotten really excited about something he kept calling a 'Magi-optic semaphore system lacking the downsides of the protean charm' and 'the wizarding world's ARPAnet'. As the pebble moved into the line formed by the first pair, the first speck of the pair flashed and hissed, causing a chain reaction in the rest. A few moments later, the second speck flashed at him.

"Time for messsage: two partss in thoussand."

Colin smiled. It looked like that communication was definitely faster than sound, but slower than light. A lot of that could be processing bottlenecks, though. He'd need to work on that. As he lifted his wand to dispel the specks, he doubled over. It felt like a sword was stabbing him in the mind and cutting away at his identity. As he collapsed, eyes watering with the pain, a black dog seemed to materialize from the shadows before blurring into a man. The man walked over to him, looking with no small amount of pity at his writhing body.

"Look, kid, I'm just going to say in advance that I wish it didn't have to be this way. If it's any consolation, this isn't personal. It's just business."

The last thing Colin saw before blacking out was the man pulling out a pair of scissors and cutting off a lock of his hair. Then his world went dark.

Sirius dropped the young wizard's hair into a flask of Polyjuice, grinning as it turned a light blue. It looked like this one would taste reasonably good, unlike some of the other jobs he'd done. He downed the vial, grimacing as his body warped and shrunk until it matched that of the child currently passed out on the dirt. He never got used to that feeling, At least the potion preserved his magic and he didn't need to deal with some...he searched through the information his Legilimency had brought him to find the age of the child...some second year's magic and the Ministry's damned trace. That would be intolerable.

With a flick of his wand, Sirius' clothes became identical to that of the child. With another flick and a muttered word, the boy's body and the flask disappeared. He wouldn't need them for a while. A third cast changed the appearance of his wand to that of the boy's. Now for the fiddly part about stealing someone's identity. He concentrated, bringing the information he'd gleaned from Legilimency to the forefront of his mind. He lifted his wand, pointing it at his own temple while focusing on linking the duration of his next spell to that of the polyjuice.

"Confundus!"

Colin blinked a few times. Why did his head hurt? And what was he doing? After a few seconds of confused looking around, he caught sight of the specks and relaxed. He was experimenting with Sapespeck tonight, of course. If his current fuzziness was anything to go by, he probably needed to get some sleep. The research could wait.

When he arrived back at his house, his father waved to him from his seat by the television.

"How's your summer project going, Col? Anything you can tell Dennis about?"

"Not yet, Da." Colin smiled. His little brother was so eager to learn about magic, and Colin couldn't really blame him. When he had first found out about magic, he had been so excited that he'd almost...what? Why couldn't he remember what had happened?

His father noticed his discomfort.

"Col, are you ok? You look a bit pale. Is this something to do with magic?"

Colin shrugged.

"Probably not, Da. I'm just feeling a little tired, is all. I'll be better in the morning."

"I'll hold you to that, you know." Mr. Creevey's eyes twinkled, and Colin laughed.

"I know, Da. Good night!"

Colin went up to the second floor and into his room, falling into a dreamless sleep almost the instant his head hit the bed.

XxX

August 28th, 1993, 10 am: 3 days before Hogwarts opens

"Mrs. Babbage, was it?"

The voice jerked Voldemort out of his reverie. Somehow even a wizard with his mental reserves couldn't manage to stay focused in the Ministry's Property Allocations office. There was something about the place that seemed to drain the energy from anyone inside.

He lifted his head.

"Yes, that's me. Can I come in?"

The attendant at the door nodded.

"Yes, Mr. Rimble will see you now."

Voldemort stood, still a little shaky on his feet after this most recent set of bodily modifications. While it wasn't strictly necessary to modify his height and weight to avoid being seen as Bellatrix(after all, he had of course already changed his face and hair color) it never hurt to be too careful.

The attendant led him down a short hallway into a small room which almost looked like a cubicle. Everything about the room, from the N.E.W.T scores posted on the wall to the obnoxiously shiny nameplate on the desk in the center, suggested that its occupant felt a good deal more pride in his pointless middle manager job than was deserved. A few moments after he sat down, the desk's occupant turned to face him.

"Good morning, Mrs. Babbage. My name is James Rimble, and I am your ministry-assigned Property Acquisitions representative. Why are you here this morning?"

Voldemort sighed. The ministry, it seemed, was as delightfully incompetent as it had always been. Ah well, at least he could blow off some steam winding up idiots.

"Well, Mr. Rimble, it should already say that in my file. But, since you don't seem to have that, I'm planning to move into Hogsmeade."

The man's face reddened slightly.

"All right, you don't need to be snarky. I just wanted to make sure your reasons matched with what we had on file."

"To make sure I didn't lie about my reason for coming? I somehow doubt that happens enough to warrant this."

Rimble's eyes flashed with annoyance.

"Look, ma'am, that's not what we're here to talk about. I'm going to need to ask you to stop being confrontational."

Voldemort raised his hands in acceptance. Time to soothe some ruffled feathers.

"I'm sorry, Mr. Rimble. I've just had such an abominable time getting here that I've lost some of my tact."

The man laughed companionably.

"I can understand that, Mrs. Babbage. I'll try to get this done as quickly as possible, ok?"

"That would be excellent, thanks."

Rimble smiled.

"Ok. Now, before I give you your permit for Hogsmeade residence and access key to the wards, I'm going to need you to answer some questions for our files, ok? Security's gotten a bit tighter around there lately, because of the Tower and all."

Voldemort nodded.

"Of course. Ask away."

"First off, have you taken any trips in the past 5 years?"

"Yes," Voldemort nodded. "I went to visit my son on the Continent around a month ago. He lives in Paris. I left on the 25th of July and returned on the 2nd of August."

Rimble pulled out a file and glanced at it.

"Ok, that checks out. Thanks for giving me the extra information, it cuts out some of the other questions I'd have needed to ask. Why are you moving to Hogsmeade?"

"Some of my relatives live there and they've been after me for a while to join them. Now that my son's out of the house, I can move there even though it means taking a smaller home. Also, with my husband gone, I'm a bit low on income, and Hogsmeade's cheaper than London."

The man paused for a moment to update the file before turning back to Voldemort.

"Might I ask what happened to your husband?"

"He worked in the Department of Mysteries, doing god-knows-what. There...was an accident. I never even got to see the body-" It only took a little effort to bring tears to his eyes and fake choking back a sob.

Rimble's eyes widened.

"Ma'am, I didn't mean to bring back sad memories. I'll fast track you through the approval process, ok?"

Voldemort nodded, wiping the tears from his face.

"Thank-thank you, James. When can I move in?"

"I'll do my best to make sure you can by tomorrow, Ma'am. Any more questions?"

"No. Can I go?"

The man nodded and Voldemort stood up, leaving the room. That had been about as easy as expected.

A/N: After many months, SBatPD is back! I've many, many plans for this story, and hopefully I can see them all come to fruition. There are some slight changes from GWatSI, mainly to characterization.

Chapter 3: Dissimulation, Pt II, Sufficiently Accurate Simulations

The confundus charm is unique among nearly all charms in its method. Like many other spells(such as, say, Imperio) it is meant to control the actions of the victim. However, unlike Imperio and Legilimentic control, the spell does not implant low level hypnotic commands into the mind of the subject. Rather, it appears to override parts of the subject's consciousness entirely, replacing those portions with the caster's desired thoughts, memories, and emotions. This makes the spell simultaneously far more dangerous and more versatile. On the one hand, an inexpert caster can leave their victim a drooling, unrecoverable wreck, replacing their minds with half-built thoughts. On the other hand, an expert can change a person on a far more delicate level, slightly modifying various parts of their minds to create the perfect sleeper agent. In effect, the confundus charm is the scalpel to Imperio's hammer. It takes far more practice to use, but can do far more.

To explain the relevancy of the charm to our mission, consider this: Confundus works on any human being with a magical core, including those who have unfortunately been Kissed or who are brain dead. A skilled legilimens can recover enough information from a person's mind to emulate them through a confundus in minutes, if not less. The implications are clear. Magical transfer of consciousness is possible.

-Research log, section X: Conclusions and evaluations. Subsection II: Consciousness emulation(Tower of hogwarts, July 1993)

XxX

August 31, 1993: 1 day prior to Hogwarts' opening

Colin struggled to wake. It looked like he had had the dream again. His eyes opened and he groaned to find that his sheets were soaked with sweat, just like they had been for the past 5 nights. He really needed to figure out what was going on because this kind of sleep deprivation would seriously screw up his research and could damage his mind. He closed his eyes, trying to reconstruct the dream. After a few seconds, the dream flew back to him, playing behind his eyelids almost against his will.

Hands too large extend from a body that's too big, it's TOO BIG and he can't control it and it's reaching for another him, that's another HIM there on the floor and he looks sick and doesn't move. The hands move and a bit of the other him's hair falls off and he can't understand why any of this is happening, he tries to think about it rationally like Harry taught him but his brain feels like it's broken and missing pieces and before he can even start thinking about that the hands twitch again and there's blue liquid flowing down his throat. Then there is darkness.

His eyes snapped open. He hadn't seen the blue liquid before. That gave him something to work on. He feverishly unzipped his bag and flung out the carefully packed books until he found what he was looking for: his potions textbook. He flipped to the image-based index(one of the features of the new books, Harry had insisted on it for some reason and for the life of him he couldn't remember why, he couldn't remember anything like he should be able to but now wasn't the time to think of problems, now was the time to solve them) and scanned down the page, trying to find anything that could possibly be the liquid from his dreams. Eventually, he caught sight of two potions in a section marked 'Advanced: Only present for demonstrative purposes'. The first was a dark blue, slightly different from the color in his dreams: the Draught of Peace. According to the textbook, the potion served as an emotional depressant and a sedative. Given his dreams, that...didn't seem likely. On the other hand, maybe the weird color was because the potion was prepared incorrectly.

The next potion threw him for a loop: Wolfsbane. The potion was a bright blue, just like he remembered from his dream. Also, its user needed to take it every night for a week before the full moon. If the sky the night before was anything to go by, the full moon would be the next day, if not earlier. That didn't explain the hands, and the other him, but it seemed to make a kind of sense. There was one thing that he needed to check, though. With a goal in mind, Colin walked downstairs and greeted his father.

"Good morning, Da."

Mr. Creevey smiled, though some concern still lingered in his eyes. He knew Colin wasn't sleeping well.

"That it is, Col. How are you feeling?"

Colin shrugged.

"A bit better, Da. How's Dennis?"

Colin's father beamed. "He's doing excellently. He sent me a letter this morning saying that he'd just finished getting the last of his books."

"That's good." Colin fell silent, staring at his father for a few moments.

"Yes, son?"

"I have a question: when I came back from research Wednesday night, did you see any scratches or cuts on my body? Small scrapes, even?"

His father tilted his head for a few seconds, thinking.

"No, son, I can't say you did. You were really pale though. It looked like something had scared you out there. Why?"

"I think...I think I might know why I've been having bad dreams." Colin hesitated.

"Why?" His father urged.

"I...I might be a werewolf. I don't know for sure, and I think that I've been taking potions to fix it. I think that I've been forcing myself to take those potions before making myself forget the experience."

Mr. Creevey's eyes widened and he fell silent for a few seconds, clearly stunned.

"Son...you want to run that by me again? I think I must have misheard."

"Sure, Da. See, the morning after I got home, I checked my wand, and the most spell I'd fired that night was meant to implant commands. Also, I've been having dreams where I drink a potion that looks like one called Wolfsbane. I think I got bitten by a werewolf out there and then used the spell to make sure I'd drink Wolfsbane and not remember drinking it, but I screwed it up slightly so now I remember in dreams."

"...what exactly should I be doing about this, Colin? It sounds like you're in danger, and I have no idea how to help. Should I write the professor that took you and Dennis to buy your books?"

Colin sighed.

"I don't know if there's anything you can do, Da. I don't want to tell her what I think it is in case I'm wrong. Look, I'll be at Hogwarts tomorrow night, and I'll ask the healers to check me over, ok? If this is what I think it is, then I'll be fine."

His father nodded unwillingly.

"If you say so, Col. If you say so."

"Nothing's going to happen to me this year, Da." Colin smiled. "I promise."

XxX

August 31, 1993: one day prior to Hogwarts opening.

9:52 am

Stupefy et Signa!

A red bolt flickered along a dark hallway before sharply curving in midair to slam into a seemingly nondescript wall. A few seconds later, a high, clear sound rang out and a green light shone for a brief moment before shutting off. Harry James Potter-Evans-Verres took note of the light for a moment before turning to a notebook and activating his dictation quill.

Test 101a result: Strings of enchantments can be linked to specific casting words and gestures as a compression method. This suggests that spells as we know them are based enough in the mind of the caster that the caster can, to some extent, combine various spells into a new spell.

After he fell silent, he leaned back against a wall as his eyes closed. Combining spell strings was a taxing mental exercise, even for him. Especially given his particular...versions of the task. On the other hand, he was yielding results! In only a few months, he'd have some basic enchantment sequences finetuned to the point that he could teach them to others!

As he relaxed, Hermione appeared out of a seeming void next to him. That particular trick had taken her a few months and a lot of research into the refractive properties of pressurized air.

"Harry, are you ok?"

He opened his mouth to answer, but she cut him off.

"Why am I even asking you this question, of course you aren't, look at you. You've been working on this one set of experiments for how many hours straight now? 30? 40?"

Harry sheepishly nodded.

"45 or so, actually, but that isn't especially relevant. I did get some sleep in the interim period. And I need to finish this as soon as possible! Spell strings could massively hasten the stasis process! My work might be tiring but I'm saving lives."

Hermione sighed.

"That was true of the polyjuice research too. And the low level command system for healer reflexes. And the consciousness emulation systems. In fact, if I'm not wrong, every project you've been working on since the Amortentia...incident fit that qualification, did they not?"

"And?"

"Harry, you can't keep doing this to yourself!" Hermione snapped. Her magic seemed to press down on the room. "You're burning yourself out, and I won't just sit by and watch it happen. You won't do this alone, Harry-" She cut herself off before her next words could leave her mouth but they reverberated in her mind. 'because I swore on my life and magic that you'd never have to.'

He caught sight of her expression and whitened.

"Hermione, it's ok. I'll pull back on the experiments for now. I just had my first successful result, anyway."

Her demeanor instantly changed and she stepped closer to him.

"Really? What was it?"

He smiled and raised his wand.

"Observe."

He flicked his wand 3 times at the wall to his left.

Luminos! Stuporfy tenues! Lux sopitum!

The wall lit up briefly before a stunner slammed into it. A moment later, the spot hit by the stunner glowed a faint green. Hermione tilted her head, confused.

"Yes? You've shown me this combination before. Is there something I should be seeing?"

Harry grinned and twisted his wand once.

Stupefy et Signa!

The same set of effects repeated themselves at a slightly faster pace. Hermione's eyes widened as she smiled.

"You figured out spell strings! What was causing the issue?"

"Something about holding every spell in mind simultaneously was a mental stumbling block. I ended up bypassing it by-" Harry's voice froze. A few seconds later, he cursed under his breath.

"Looks like the Vow blocked that one. So be it."

"It's that dangerous?" The secondary, real question was not missed by either of them.

"I don't know, Hermione. I was able to think about teaching healers to do it. I just don't know. Anyway, why'd you come to see me?"

She smiled again, a smaller, weaker smile this time.

"I wanted to remind you that the school year starts tomorrow. Ready for third year?"

A/N: Sorry for the slight delay, the second half of this chapter was difficult to write. The next chapter(either Dissimulation III: Foreground and Background, or Foregrounds and Backgrounds I) should be out in about 2 weeks.

I feel now's as good a time to say it as any: all facts in this story(whether about the canon-verse, MoR-verse, the stuff I'm preserving from the GWatSI-verse or about physical stuff like full moon) are meant to be accurate. If you find mistakes, please tell me(sources if you would).

Plotwise: The chapter title is directly relevant to all three sections of the chapter, and figuring out how will help the reader figure out Harry's method for spell strings.

Please review!